Kelly Ann Marshall

Web Development

MSc Information Technology (Merit) +44 (0)7906 117 249 kelly_ann_marshall@yahoo.com https://kellyannmarshall.github.io

Summary

Experienced and talented web developer who is self-motivated, client-centric, creative, insightful and versatile. Adept at innovating user experience for web applications. Exceptional interpersonal skills and is efficient, organised, resourceful, flexible, reliable and willing to listen and contribute with clients and team members. Available for contract and permanent positions based in Glasgow City Centre or 100% remote.

Skills

- HTML(5)
- · CSS(3) / SASS / LESS
- JavaScript / Typescript
- · Angular / Vue.js
- Node / Webpack
- · Docker / AWS / Jenkins
- Git / Bitbucket / SVN
- Jasmine / Karma / Jest / Cypress
- Mapbox / OpenLayers / D3

- Jekyll / Joomla / Wordpress / Eleventy
- Responsive Web Design
- Wireframing / Prototyping
- Progressive Enhancement
- W3C Standards & Accessibility
- Adobe Creative Suite
- Balsamiq / Figma / Adobe XD
- Cross-Browser Compatibility
- Google Analytics

Professional Experience

Front-End Developer (Nov 2022 - Present)

Beeks Group, Glasgow, Scotland

Technologies: Angular, Typescript, NgRx, RxJS, D3.js, Jasmine, Storybook, Docker, Bitbucket, Jira

- Working as part of an internal development team on a network / server infrastructure self-service portal build with Angular and Python/Django.
- Developed chart components displaying server usage analytics with D3.js.
- Updated legacy code and upgraded frontend code dependencies.

Senior Developer (Aug 2020 - Jun 2022)

Idox Group (acquired thinkWhere in Oct 2021), Glasgow, Scotland

Technologies: Angular, Typescript, RxJS, OpenLayers, Python, Flask, Bootstrap, Cypress, AWS, pgAdmin, Docker, Terraform, IIS, Figma, AdobeXD, Balsamiq, Git, Jira

- Worked as part of an agile development team with a focus on design and UI development of groundMapper, a fully-featured cloud service GIS data application.
- Wireframing, UI design and front-end development of advanced search functionality, split-screen map / data views and bespoke forestry data management features.
- Development and delivery of new admin features for groundMapper including permissions and account, project and user management.
- UI design and front-end development of Eurogeographics Open Maps for Europe website, a resource for official European map, geospatial and land information.

UI Developer (Aug 2018 - Feb 2020)

VisitScotland, Edinburgh, Scotland

Technologies: HTML5, CSS3, SASS, VueJS, JavaScript / ES6, MapboxGL, Webpack, Gulp, Cypress, VSCode, BloomReach Experience CMS, Freemarker, Bitbucket, Jira

- Worked as part of an internal development team tasked with a major re-platforming project for VisitScotland's flagship website, www.visitscotland.com.
- Created proof of concept interactive tourism destination maps focussed on accessibility and with rich
 features including filtering and sorting destination product and event data on name, product type, rating,
 price and date.
- Worked with UX, Design and Software Engineering teams to create complex itinerary CMS templates integrating destination product data and itinerary maps.

Front-End Developer (Aug 2017 - May 2018)

Peninsula Business Services, Glasgow, Scotland

Technologies: HTML5, CSS3, LESS, AngularJS, JavaScript / ES6, Node, Gulp, Git, Karma, Jasmine, VSCode, Jenkins, WebAPIs, Microsoft Team Foundation Server

- HTML, CSS/LESS and JavaScript development for an internal task management system built as a single page web application using AngularJS.
- Liaised with development team to research and implement Postcode Anywhere API service in a client address search and entry feature.
- Refactored project CSS/LESS directory structure and added automated css code linting to the project, making the project files easier to maintain.

Front-End Developer (Feb 2014 - May 2017)

Arnold Clark, Glasgow, Scotland

Technologies: HTML5, CSS3, SASS, JavaScript, JQuery, Node, Git, Backbone, Jekyll, Joomla, Jasmine

- As part of an agile web development team, I worked on the client-side HTML, CSS/SASS and JavaScript development for Arnold Clark's rental and leasing websites, which included:
 - https://www.arnoldclarkrental.com
 - https://www.autocentre.acvm.com
 - https://www.acvm.com

Education

Master of Science in Information Technology (Sep 2010 - Sep 2011)

University of Glasgow, Glasgow, Scotland

Emphasis: Programming in Java, JavaScript, PHP, MySQL, XML, HTML, CSS, Django, Python, Multimedia Systems, Software Project Management, Information Systems and Databases

Dissertation: A web Interface for the purchase of live event tickets with interactive venue maps built with SVG, JavaScript, PHP and MySQL

Activities: Postgraduate Student Representative

Bachelor of Fine Arts in Photography (Sep 1989 - Jun 1993)

Maryland Institute, College of Art, Baltimore, Maryland

Emphasis: B&W and colour photography and development, film and video production, photochemistry, alternative photo processes, studio lighting, 2D design, computer illustration, painting, drawing, sculpture, art history and the history of photography